- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[wacky upbeat music]
[古怪欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [gulping nosily]
- [大声吞咽]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- [slurping and popping]
- [发出声音和爆裂声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[plate squeaking]
- [moaning]
[盘子吱吱作响]
- [呻吟]
- [groaning]
- [belching]
- [打嗝]
- [growling fiercely]
- [激烈咆哮]
[steam whistle blows]
[蒸汽哨声响起]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Another rotten day
at the Krusty Krab!
又是烂日
在蟹堡王！
[silence]
[沉默]
[all chomping nosily]
[大家都吵闹地咀嚼着]
Not that anyone's listening.
并不是有人在听。
Huh?
啊？
- I'm listening, Squidward.
Tell SpongeBob your troubles.
- 我在听，章鱼哥。
告诉海绵宝宝你的烦恼。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[microphone squeals]
[麦克风尖叫声]
- [sighs]
If you must know,
- [叹气]
如果你一定要知道的话，
I'm stuck in a dead-end job
working at this grease trap.
我陷入了一个没有出路的工作
在这个隔油池工作。
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- My tentacles hurt.
- 我的触手受伤了。
And I live next door
to the number one
而我就住在隔壁
到第一名
most annoying neighbor
in Bikini Bottom.
最烦人的邻居
在比基尼底部。
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
- Whoo!
Number one!
- 呼！
第一！
- One more annoying thing,
and I'm gonna lose it.
- 还有一件烦人的事，
我会失去它。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- [sighs]
And there it is.
- [叹气]
就是这样。
- Your Krabby Patty meal, sir.
- 您的蟹肉饼餐，先生。
- Huh?
- 啊？
Ew!
呃！
Fingernails.
指甲。
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- That's worse than a hair!
- 这比头发还糟糕！
- [gulping]
- [吞咽]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Ew.
- 呃。
- SpongeBob, would you
stop biting your nails?
- 海绵宝宝，你愿意吗
别再咬指甲了吗？
- Oh, Squidward,
I never bite my nails.
-哦，章鱼哥，
我从来不咬指甲。
- What do you call that?
- 你管它叫什么？
- [yelps]
Oh.
- [尖叫声]
哦。
- Ugh, nail-biting
is a disgusting bad habit,
- 呃，咬指甲
是一种令人厌恶的坏习惯
so quit it!
所以戒掉吧！
- I promise not to bite
my nails ever again.
- 我保证不咬人
我的指甲再次出现。
- Ahem!
- 咳咳！
- [laughs]
Oops.
- [笑]
哎呀。
I guess biting my
nails has become a bad habit.
我猜想咬我的
剪指甲已经成为一种坏习惯。
Oh, breaking this
nail-biting habit'll be a snap.
哦，打破这个
咬指甲的习惯很快就会养成。
[chewing nosily]
[大声咀嚼]
Just have to keep
my nails away...
只需要保留
我的指甲离开...
From my mouth.
从我嘴里说出来。
Simple.
简单的。
Huh? Ugh...
啊？啊...
[chewing nosily]
[大声咀嚼]
I need a plan B.
我需要一个B计划。
[light whimsical music]
[轻快的异想天开的音乐]
♪ ♪
There, now my nails
are too pretty to bite.
那里，现在我的指甲
太漂亮了，舍不得咬。
Huh?
啊？
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Oh.
哦。
- [meows]
- What's that?
- [喵]
- 那是什么？
Oh, what
a great idea, Gary.
哦，什么
好主意，加里。
A walk would
really clear my head.
散步会
我的头脑真的很清醒。
[light playful music]
[轻快俏皮的音乐]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
Ah, I just needed
a breath of fresh water.
啊，我只是需要
呼吸新鲜的水。
[sniffs]
Ah.
[嗅嗅]
啊。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
That'll take care of it.
这样就可以搞定了。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Oh, don't do it.
哦，别这样做。
Don't do it.
不要这样做。
Well...I do'd it.
嗯……我做到了。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Time for stronger measures.
是时候采取更强有力的措施了。
All right, self, let's see
ya get out of that one.
好吧，自己，让我们看看
你离开那个吧。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Whoa, SpongeBob,
are you okay?
- 哇哦，海绵宝宝，
你还好吗？
- [gasp]
Fred, your nails.
- [喘气]
弗雷德，你的指甲。
They're so...beautiful.
她们是如此……美丽。
- Aw, thanks.
I really pride myself on--
- 哦，谢谢。
我真的很自豪——
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- My nails!
- 我的指甲！
- [laughing]
Must bite nails.
- [笑]
一定要咬指甲。
[laughs menacingly]
[威胁性地笑]
- [humming]
Give me the works, Ethel.
- [嗡嗡声]
把作品给我，埃塞尔。
Ugh, my nails
are in terrible shape.
呃，我的指甲
状况很糟糕。
[moans]
[呻吟声]
Ooh, that feels good.
哦，感觉不错。
- [chomping]
- [stammering] Ethel,
- [咀嚼]
- [结结巴巴]埃塞尔，
you know I like to keep
my nails long--
你知道我喜欢保留
我的指甲很长——
[shouting]
[喊叫]
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
- So when should we schedule
your next appointment?
- 那么我们应该什么时候安排
你的下一次约会？
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [groans]
- SpongeBob!
- [呻吟]
- 海绵宝宝！
Trying out a new
look with your face?
尝试新的
用脸看？
- [chomping]
- I like it!
- [咀嚼]
- 我喜欢它！
- Oh, Patrick, I can't stop...
- 哦，帕特里克，我无法停止......
biting my fingernails.
咬我的指甲。
- Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
- 唔。
嗯嗯。
Ha! I know just what you need!
哈!我知道你需要什么！
[laughs]
[笑]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[people screaming]
[人们尖叫]
Glove World makes me
forget all my troubles...
手套世界让我
忘记我所有的烦恼...
and my name.
和我的名字。
- You're right.
- 你说得对。
I've forgotten all
about biting my...
我已经全部忘记了
关于咬我的...
nails!
指甲！
[howling]
[嚎叫]
[shouts]
[喊叫]
- Huh.
- 嗯。
- Hey you, gimme that.
- 嘿你，给我那个。
Knuckle 22 to base.
指节 22 至底座。
We've got a nail-biter
in Pinky Land.
我们有一个咬指甲的人
在粉红之地。
[both shouting]
[两人大喊]
- [chomping]
I think--I think...
- [咀嚼]
我想——我想……
I need help.
[chomping]
我需要帮助。
[咀嚼]
- [line trills]
Cheeks residence.
- [台词颤音]
脸颊住所。
- Sandy!
- 桑迪！
[chomping]
[bell dings]
[咀嚼]
[铃声]
- Hmm.
- 唔。
- [chomping]
[bell dings]
- [咀嚼]
[铃声]
- Aww.
- 哇。
- [chomping]
[bell dings]
- [咀嚼]
[铃声]
- Don't worry, SpongeBob.
- 别担心，海绵宝宝。
We'll stop your nail-biting
habit quicker than
我们会阻止你咬指甲
习惯比
a jet-powered jackrabbit!
喷气动力长耳大野兔！
This'll keep your fingers
out of your kisser.
这会让你的手指
从你的吻中出来。
- I sure hope so.
- 我当然希望如此。
- Ah.
- Mmm.
- 啊。
- 嗯。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Oh...uh-uh.
- 哦...呃-呃。
Tell me he ain't doing
what I think he's doing.
告诉我他没有做
我认为他在做什么。
- Oh, he's good.
- 哦，他很好。
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- SpongeBob,
that's just plain wrong.
- 海绵宝宝，
这完全是错误的。
I guess we're gonna
have to watch you
我想我们会
必须看着你
like Mr. Krabs
watches his bank account!
像蟹老板一样
监视他的银行账户！
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- Huh?
- 啊？
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
Oh!
哦！
[both snoring]
[两人都打呼噜]
What, what?
Where'd he go?
什么，什么？
他去哪儿了？
[unintelligible shouting]
[难以理解的喊叫]
- [chomping]
Hi, Sandy.
- [咀嚼]
嗨，桑迪。
- It's high time we got
you some professional help.
- 我们是时候了
你一些专业的帮助。
This doctor's
the best hypnotherapist
这位医生的
最好的催眠治疗师
in Bikini Bottom.
在比基尼底部。
He'll sort out
your bad habit.
他会解决的
你的坏习惯。
- The doctor will see you now,
Mr. SquarePants.
- 医生现在就来看你，
方裤先生。
- Oh, please relax,
Mr. SquarePants.
- 哦，请放松，
方裤先生。
Now, what seems
to be the trouble?
现在看来，什么
成为麻烦？
- Doctor, I can't stop...
- 医生，我无法停止...
I can't stop...
我无法停止...
I can't stop biting my nails!
我忍不住咬指甲！
I don't know what to do.
我不知道该怎么办。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- Well, let us take a peek
into your subconscious
- 好吧，让我们看一下
进入你的潜意识
and see what
is causing your problem.
看看什么
导致了你的问题。
Keep your eyes on the watch,
Mr. SquarePants.
眼睛一直盯着手表，
方裤先生。
Watch the watch,
Mr. SquarePants.
看手表，
方裤先生。
- Watch the watch...
Watch the watch...
- 看手表...
看手表...
[woozily]
Watch the watch.
[昏昏沉沉]
看手表。
- What seems to be troubling
you, Mr. SquarePants?
- 似乎有什么令人烦恼的事情
你，方裤先生吗？
- I can't stop...
biting my...
- 我无法停止...
咬我的...
nails.
指甲。
- Why do you want
to bite your nails?
- 你为什么想要
咬指甲？
- Stuck in dead-end job.
- 陷入了没有出路的工作。
Work in a grease trap.
在隔油池中工作。
- Go on.
- 继续。
- Tentacles hurt.
- 触手受伤了。
- Tentacles?
Hmm, interesting.
- 触手？
嗯，有趣。
- Neighbor...SpongeBob...
- 邻居...海绵宝宝...
annoying.
恼人的。
- But aren't you SpongeBob,
Mr. SquarePants?
- 但你不是海绵宝宝吗
方裤先生？
- No...I am Squidward.
- 不...我是章鱼哥。
- [gasp]
Mr. SquarePants!
- [喘气]
方裤先生！
Obviously,
you have subconsciously
显然，
你潜意识里有
internalized Mr. Squidward's
problems as your own.
内化了章鱼哥先生的
问题当成自己的问题。
When I snap my fingers,
you'll realize
当我打响指的时候
你会意识到
you are not Squidward.
You are SpongeBob,
你不是章鱼哥。
你是海绵宝宝，
and your desire to bite
your nails will--
和你想咬的欲望
你的指甲会——
Poof!
Disappear.
噗！
消失。
[snaps fingers]
- [gasps]
[打响指]
- [喘气]
Am I cured?
我痊愈了吗？
- Yeah, you are cured.
- 是的，你已经痊愈了。
- Whoopee!
Thanks, Doctor...
- 哎哟！
谢谢，医生...
Doctor...
医生...
Hans!
汉斯！
[gasps]
[喘气]
Giant, delicious
fingernails!
巨大，好吃
指甲！
- [shouts]
Mr. SquarePants, please!
- [喊叫]
方裤先生，请！
- Doctor Hans,
I'm here for my weekly
- 汉斯医生，
我来这里是为了我的每周
appointment--
预约 -
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- I'm going to need
therapy for my therapy...
- 我需要
治疗为我的治疗...